Allef Rodrigo Schmidt

Rio Grande do Norte. Brazil



allefschmidt@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/schmidt-maker

Summary

I'm a passionate Frontend Developer with focus on web development and APIs. Familiarity with JavaScript and Python, frameworks and tools (React, Redux, FastAPI, Flask, Express, Axios, Vue.js, Node.js, Webpack e Babel.js) and DevOps/cloud deployment (mainly on Heroku). I also have 2 years of experience architecting, developing, deploying, and maintaining mobile application using React Native (iOS & Android).

5 years experience leading development teams (Web development, hardware development, science fair & robotic teams) and implementing agile methodologies, especially SCRUM + KANBAN.

I make robots as a hobby, I love 3D printing, 3D modeling, chatbots, create circuit boards, get sensors data and control some stuffs.

Experience



Full Stack Developer

ID Soft

Sep 2021 - Present (1 year +)

Through the analysis of the system requirements, I participate in the programming and tests on Android and/or iOS platforms using React Native, in addition to implementing improvements in relation to the performance of the application, both at the front-end and backend levels, also participating in any necessary corrections. aimed at meeting the needs of users.

Frontend Developer

Núcleo Acesso à Terra Urbanizada

Aug 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

I work participating in the construction of the aesthetics of a REURB digital platform in vue.js, with the objective of providing a better experience to the user who will use the system, whether through the usability, usefulness or convenience offered in the interaction with the product.

Also participated in the construction of the visualization module and dynamic interaction of maps using leaftleat, in addition to the creation of a dashboard to monitor data in real time, either to optimize processes or to monitor the performance and growth of the project.

Frontend Developer

Agrícola Famosa SA

Jun 2021 - Jan 2022 (8 months)

Responsible for maintenance and improvements in existing applications in the company, especially using the Raspberry Pi microcomputer, especially in improving the design of the application, ensuring a better user experience in its use, also working on the application of techniques to improve consumption and sending data through REST API.



Product Manager

Maker Educ

Jan 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 7 months)

Responsible for developing technical aspects of the company's strategy to ensure alignment with its commercial objectives, actively participating in the construction of the Maker Board, a printed circuit that can be transformed into a platform for programming and prototyping electronic circuits.

In addition, one of the most important assignments was to discover and implement new technologies that provide a competitive advantage over market competitors, this took place in the creation of the Maker Educ application, a multiplatform application that allows the Maker Board to be programmed directly from the student's cell phone, thus avoiding the use of a computer to implement a programming/ robotics class.



👲 Robotics Teacher

Colégio Mater Christi

Jan 2018 - Jan 2021 (3 years 1 month)

Robotics teacher for Elementary School 1, 2 and High School, also responsible for managing a laboratory, taking care of the layout, organization and arrangement of tools, in practical classes different software engineering methodologies are used, facilitating the organization and construction of projects .



Robotics Teacher

Colegio Menino Deus

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017 (1 year)

Robotics teacher for Elementary School 2 and High School, following constructivist teaching methods, the classes focused on programming logic allied to some daily activity of the students.



Robotics Coach

Universidade Federal Rural do Semi-Árido - Ufersa

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016 (2 years)

Responsible for developing educational methodologies for teaching computer content; Promote social integration and group work through robotics workshops; Preparation for the OBR (Olimpiada Brasileira de Robótica); Ministering Educational Robotics Workshops for municipal public school children



Team Manager

Claro Brasil

Jun 2014 - Oct 2014 (5 months)

Manager of technical operations and facilities logistics for the company Master Construções Serviços LTDA, a company accredited by Claro telecommunications.

Team Lead Manager

TCM - Sistema Oeste de Comunicação

Jan 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Supervise teleservice teams, ensuring good service and productivity, in addition to providing support during service at all stages, including doubts, compliments, suggestions and complaints.

Education

m Metrópole Digital - IMD/UFRN

Ensino Técnico, Desenvolvedor Web

Jan 2021 - Jan 2021

Perfil profissional: desenvolve e mantém projetos para a web; utiliza linguagens de programação, banco de dados e recursos para a segurança da informação; utiliza recursos de imagens, vídeos, animações, linguagens de marcação e folha de estilo para desenvolvimento web.

Universidade Federal Rural do Semi-Árido

Bacharelado, Ciência da Computação 2015 - 2022

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Educator Nível 1 - Google

Issued Dec 2020 - Expires Dec 2023 PR000040

Skills

Desenvolvimento de front-end • React.js • JavaScript • Metodologias ágeis • HTML • CSS • C • JQuery • Linux • Node.js

Honors & Awards



Dec 2016

Orientou equipe que utilizou diversos recursos para seu Projeto de Inovação para ajudá-la a ter uma compreensão integral de seu problema. Além disso, tem uma solução criativa e bem fundamentada e comunica efetivamente suas descobertas aos juízes e à comunidade.

Prêmio Técnico - FIRST LEGO League

Dec 2016

Técnicos e mentores inspiram suas equipes a fazer seu melhor, tanto individualmente quanto em conjunto, e, sem eles, a FIRST LEGO League não existiria. Este prêmio vai para o técnico ou mentor cuja liderança e orientação são evidentes e exemplificam os Core Values da FIRST LEGO League da melhor forma possível.